### Aleksandr Nikitin

Antalya, Turkey / remote / relocation



**+79675608829** +905349897508

### **Data Analyst**

Solid technical background. Hold a Master of Science (MSc) degree in geoscience, majoring in Seismic Data Processing and Analysis. Had worked with geophysical data (processing, analyzing and interpreting) for 12 year. After one year of transition from geoscience to Data Analysis, I've been Data Analyst in a Fintech company since June 2021. Achieved the 7th place at the open Data Analyst 2021 competition held by Career Factory. Winner of an internal Data Analyst Hackaton 2022.

Practicing critical and business-oriented thinking. Love to plan and manage priorities. Know how to focus and get things done. Enjoy studying and advocate a continuous learning approach. Strong communication skills and a proficient English user (C1).

### **Technical Skills:**

- Python, Pandas, Numpy, sklearn
- Seaborn, Matplotlib, Plotly
- SQL (Oracle, ClickHouse)
- Git, Airflow
- scipy.stats, statsmodels
- A/B testing, bootstrap, cuped

- Tableau, Power Bi, Redash
- Product metrics 7
- Unit economics
- Stakeholder management
- Reporting and presentations
- MS Excel, PowerPoint, Word, Project

## **Professional Experience**

June 2021 - Present: Data Analyst → Middle Data Analyst, Tochka Bank

Use Python and SQL on a daily basis to help business make data driven decisions.

- design A/B experiments to validate ML models implementation
- discovered and analyzed 2 new data sources that will be used in 2 new products
- coded 2 ETL scripts that runs daily and save up to 3 hours of work per week
- made 4 data sources to be user-friendly and accessible for sales team without technical skills
- look for insights in data
- present analytical reports to colleagues, product teams and internal customers
- facilitate team meetings (scrum daily, sprint planning sessions, retro meetings)

2015 - 2020: Head of Data Processing Department → CTO, Geology Without Limits Group. Was in charge of development a new marine seismic data acquisition technology, leading offshore seismic data acquisition and processing projects, business development, product management.

- organized and managed 2 offshore seismic data acquisition projects
- supervised 3 seismic data processing projects
- developed with a team a new marine long-offset seismic data acquisition technology
- managed full-cycle Research and Development process and manufacturing of 3 revisions of seismic recording units (totaling 120 recording units)
- secured 300k USD investments for equipment trials
- 8 technical abstracts and presentations on Geophysical conferences and workshops
- adopted Kanban for the company



nktn.lx@gmail.com

2010 – 2015: Seismic Data Processing Geophysicist → Senior Seismic Data Processing Geophysicist → Lead Seismic Data Processing Geophysicist, Seismo-Shelf LLC Participated in different offshore seismic data acquisition and processing projects worldwide: Russian Arctics, India, Bulgaria, Norway, Kazakhstan.

- spent 1 year living in India and processing seismic data for ONGC
- spent 6 month living in Norway and processing seismic data for Wintershall
- built velocity tomographic models for 3 deep crustal research projects
- equipment maintenance and data QC on 5 offshore 4C nodes seismic surveys
- seismic data processing training for new employees (Processing software: Focus, Echos, GeoDepth, SeisSpace ProMAX, Vista 2D/3D, X-Tomo)

# **2008 – 2010: Junior Seismic Data Processing Geophysicist**, All-Russia Petroleum Research Exploration Institute (VNIGRI)

Seismic data analysis and interpretation, Eastern Siberia Regional Department.

- seismic data analysis and interpretation
- seismogeological modeling activities and calculations of reserves
- AVO-modeling technical abstract and presentation on scientific conference for young geoscientists

### **Education**

**Majored in:** Seismic Data Processing and Analysis, Department of geophysical and geochemical methods of exploration activities, Saint Petersburg State Mining University, 2010

### **Professional retraining**

- «Teamlead 101», Stratoplan Management School, 2 months, July 2022
- «sklearn ML course», France Université Numérique, 3 months, May 2022
- «Data Analysis Course», karpov.courses, 5 month, June 2021
- «Data Analysis Course», Tinkoff and Moscow State University, 3 months, May 2021
- «Data Analyst Professional Development Programme», Yandex Praktikum & University 20.35), 2 months, March 2021
- «Data Science Math Skills», Coursera Duke University, 1 months, October 2020
- «Computer Science Career Path», Codecademy, 5 months, July 2020

## **Data Analysis Portfolio on GitHub**

---> go to repo..